Ilgiz Murzakhanov

E-mail: ilgmu@elektro.dtu.dk Phone: +79854443802 / +4552643102

Location: Copenhagen, Denmark LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ilmur/

> Background

"Technical University of Denmark"

• Ph.D. "Electrical and Electronics Engineering"

GPA: 11.75/12

Thesis: "Data-driven Optimization of Distribution Grids"

"Skolkovo Institute of Science and Technology"

• M.Sc. "Energy Science and Technology"

GPA: 4.95/5 (with honors)

Thesis: "Decentralized Optimal Power Flow Under Security Constraints"

National Research University "Moscow Power Engineering Institute"

B.Sc. "Electric Power Engineering and Electrical Engineering"

GPA: 4.81/5

• Thesis: "Electrical Power Network Engineering with Research of Loss of Power and Energy Calculation Methods in all its Elements"

> Research interests

Data-driven Optimization, Interpretability of Neural Networks, Integration of Renewables in Power Systems, Smart Grids, Power Systems Analysis and Optimization

> Work experience

Doctoral Researcher at "Technical University of Denmark"

Research in decentralized optimization of distribution grids and building interpretable neural networks for forecasting in power systems

Research Assistant at "Technical University of Denmark"

Contributor to the "Indo-Danish Collaboration for Data-driven Control and Optimization for a Highly Efficient Distribution Grid" project

Research Intern at "Skolkovo Institute of Science and Technology"

Leader of the code development team for the "Grid Optimization Competition", announced by ARPA-E

Researcher at "Delft University of Technology"

"High Accuracy Simulations on Power Flows" in the Numerical Analysis Group of Prof. Vuik

Intern at R&D Center of "FGC UES"

Design of the algorithm for distributed optimization of transmission systems

1st category specialist at National Research University "MPEI"

- 5 settled contracts for a total amount of more than 130 million rubles, including "Updating the schemes of 110-220 kV electric networks in the Moscow region for the needs of the Moscow Technical Development Department"
- 2 developed projects "Intelligent inverter" and "Network Consumption Management System" within the framework of the "Energopromise" competition
- Developed 6-10 kV electric circuit of Moscow for the needs of "Moscow United Energy Grid Company"

Kgs. Lyngby, **Denmark** 2019 - now

Moscow, Russia 2016 - 2018

Moscow, Russia

2012 - 2016

Kgs. Lyngby, **Denmark Sep 2019 – now**

Kgs. Lyngby, **Denmark**

Jun – Aug 2019 Moscow, Russia

2018 - 2019

Delft, Netherlands Sep – Dec 2017

> Moscow, Russia Jun – Jul 2017

Moscow, Russia 2015 - 2017

 Designed 6-10-20 kV circuit diagram for the needs of "Federal Grid Company of the Unified Energy Network"

Intern at "Magistral Power Grid Center"

• Designed the circuit diagram of the Kaliningrad regional power grid Intern at "Enel Russia"

Moscow, Russia Jul – Aug 2015 Moscow, Russia Jul 2014

• Calculations of technical and economic indicators of power plants

> Selected publications

[1] I. Murzakhanov, G. Raj, V. Kasi, G. Prashal, S. Chatzivasileiadis, N.P. Padhy. "Novel Decentralized Loss Minimization Algorithms for the Distribution System through the reactive power control of Inverters along with the LVRT Improvements which is Validated Through RTDS Simulation" (in preparation)

[2] Y. Lu, I. Murzakhanov, S. Chatzivasileiadis. "Neural network interpretability for forecasting of aggregated renewable generation" (submitted)

[3] I. Murzakhanov, S. Chatzivasileiadis. "Decentralized Model-free Loss Minimization in Distribution Grids with the Use of Inverters" (preprint)

[4] I. Murzakhanov, A. Venzke, G. S. Misyris, S. Chatzivasileiadis. "Neural Networks for Encoding Dynamic Security-Constrained Optimal Power Flow to Mixed-Integer Linear Programs" (in preparation)

[5] I. Murzakhanov, D. Pozo. "Priority Lists for Power System Updates: Locating Phasor Measurement Units". *IEEE PES PowerTech, Madrid, Spain, 27.06.2021-02.07.2021*

[6] B. Faridpak, M. Farrokhifar, I. Murzakhanov, A. Śafari. "A Series Multi-Step Approach for Operation Co-optimization of Integrated Power and Natural Gas Systems". In: *Elsevier*, 204 (2020) [7] I. Murzakhanov, A. Malakhov, E. Gryazina. "Suboptimality of Decentralized Methods for

OPF". IEEE PES PowerTech, Milan, Italy, 23.06.2019-27.06.2019

[8] I. Murzakhanov, E. Gryazina, M. Farrokhifar. "Decentralized Optimal Power Flow Under Security Constraints". *IEEE REEPE, Moscow, Russia, 14.03.2019-15.03.2019*

[9] M. Gadzhiyev, D. Kravets, I. Murzakhanov. "Cloud computing in power engineering". In: *Electricity. Transmission and distribution* 39.6 (2016), pp. 52-58. (in Russian)

[10] M. Gadzhiyev, N. Zhmurov, I. Murzakhanov. "Open Automated Demand Response". In: *Electricity. Transmission and distribution* 31.4 (2015), pp. 50-52. (in Russian)

▶ (Co-) supervised master theses

[1] Yucun Lu, "Neural network interpretability for forecasting of aggregated renewable generation and control of the aggregated load", Master thesis, DTU, 2021

[2] Dominic Scotoni, "Development and Implementation of a Distributionally Robust Chance Constrained Optimization Tool for Distribution Grids", Master thesis, DTU, 2020

> Additional education

• "Advanced Deep Learning with Keras"

DataCamp, 2020

• Ph.D./M.Sc. level course on "Decomposition techniques for energy systems applications" by guest lecturer J. Kazempour (DTU, Denmark)

Skoltech, Russia Sep 2018

• "Data Scientist with Python" track accomplishment certificate (22 DataCamp, 2018 courses, 84 hours)

> Social accomplishments

One of 100 finalists of the "Management of the Future" conference One of 20 finalists of the national "First Generation" leadership program

St. Petersburg, 2017 Moscow, 2016

> Skills

Python, Matlab, Julia, R, Stan, TensorFlow

Microsoft Office, AutoCAD, PowerFactory, PowerWorld, Siemens NX, RastrWin

English (fluent), Danish (beginner), Russian (native), Tatar (native), Turkish (intermediate)